<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>francium</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on francium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Matthew Griffith, &#34;Why Elm&#34;</title>
      <link>/blog/book-notes---matthew-griffith-why-elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book-notes---matthew-griffith-why-elm/</guid>
      <description>Elm incorporates some of the advances from the last 40 years of programming design without learning academic jargon Many pain points of frontend development don&amp;rsquo;t exist in Elm - nulls, undefined is not a function - and runtime exceptions are extremely rare Static typing, compile time checks, friendly error messages, type signature inference Some experience Elm programmers will start a program by sketching out the type signatures first to get a high-level view of what the various APIs will be, organization will look like and create a specification for the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Rsync to efficiently backup (mirror) hard drives</title>
      <link>/blog/using-rsync-to-efficiently-backup-mirror-hard-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-rsync-to-efficiently-backup-mirror-hard-drives/</guid>
      <description>The concepts discussed here are not Raspberry Pi specific and can easily be adapted for other uses.  Background I have a Raspberry Pi setup with an external hard drive that is accessible over Samba. It&amp;rsquo;s be quite reliable so far, but I wanted to backup the data to another external drive hooked up to the same Raspberry Pi.
I found a simple solution to this problem using Rsync and Systemd timers (as opposed to installing Cron and learning Cron, but if you wish, you can substitute Systemd with Cron).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to access the McMaster CAS virtual machines on Linux host</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-access-the-mcmaster-cas-virtual-machines-on-linux-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-access-the-mcmaster-cas-virtual-machines-on-linux-host/</guid>
      <description>There is a web client available, but still requires a connect to the VPN. See CAS wiki[ref 1] for more information.  Using openconnect Install openconenct
openconnect sslvpn.mcmaster.ca (try with sudo if it fails)
If nothing failed, you should be connected
Tested on Xubuntu and Debian (x86_64).
Download the VPN client for linux, *.tar.gz from https://www.mcmaster.ca/uts/network/vpn/
Download the VMWare Horizon client, *bundle from https://www.vmware.com/go/viewclients
cd to the location of both downloads</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Knights Who say... Ni</title>
      <link>/blog/the-knights-who-say...-ni/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-knights-who-say...-ni/</guid>
      <description> We are no longer the knights who say Ni! We are now the knights who say ekki-ekki-ekki-pitang-zoom-boing! Monty Python
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Usually trying to learn, sometimes writing code. Worked on various things over the years, but still have a long way to go.
A brief summary,
 Speak JavaScript, Python, Elm, Java, C, C++, and a few more (in order of experience) Know my way around a [Lin]u[ni]x CLI and common development tools Professional experience working on a web SPA frontend (Angular) and backend server Other buzzwords: SQL, Flask, Django, Node, REST, Docker, Containers, Cloud, React This was typed in Vim  If you’ve made it this far, perhaps you’d be interested in looking at some of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Zoidboard A dashboard for monitoring system activity and performance.
Python, JavaScript, SPA, Linux
Beasley Weather Station On going community project to build a weather station. Wrote most of the software that handles syncing data between the weather station and central server.
Python, Docker
Xournal (vi scrolling patch) C
DietHN Hacker News browser with keyword filtering.
JavaScript
audiosave CLI around youtube-dl for saving audio versions of YouTube videos
Python
Ticker Tape Real-time stock dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/</guid>
      <description>Now  Heller, Catch-22 Neal Stephenson, Snow Crash (audio) Luis Atencio, Functional Programming in JavaScript  2018  Foer, Moonwalking with Einstein [Review] Grahama, Hackers and Painters ★ Griffith, Why Elm [Notes] Hallam, Millionaire Teacher ★ McCarthy, The Road ★ Scalzi, Old Man&amp;rsquo;s War (audio) [Review] Weir, The Egg ★ (short story) deGrasse Tyson, Astrophysics for People in a Hurry (audio)  2017  Dawkins, Selfish Gene (audio) Doctorow, I, Robot Gladwell, Outliers: The Story of Success (audio) Kafka, The Metamorphosis Mark Richards, Microservices vs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>