<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on francium</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on francium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 20:18:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GNOME Mutli-Monitor Workspace Fix (Gnome 3.30)</title>
      <link>/blog/gnome-mutli-monitor-workspace-fix-gnome-3.30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 20:18:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gnome-mutli-monitor-workspace-fix-gnome-3.30/</guid>
      <description>workspaces_only_on_primary setting is suppose to make workspaces work correctly [1] in a multi-monitor setup.
There are older articles on the internet about enabling this option, but they won&amp;rsquo;t work with newer versions of GNOME. Prior to 3.30, I was using a very similar command which was described by Greg Cordts in his post on the subject.
After upgrading to GNOME 3.30, this way of enabling the option stopped working. After reporting this to the GNOME team as a bug, two individuals provided some very useful information,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hide YouTube&#39;s &#34;Recommended For You&#34; suggestions</title>
      <link>/blog/hide-youtubes-recommended-for-you-suggestions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 19:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hide-youtubes-recommended-for-you-suggestions/</guid>
      <description>One thing I find quite annoying with YouTube is &amp;ldquo;Recommended For You&amp;rdquo; spam in the related videos section. I do not sign into YouTube and use Firefox Containers so most &amp;ldquo;Recommended For You&amp;rdquo; videos are irrelevant, distracting, and seem suspiciously like they&amp;rsquo;ve been paid for (I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is true).
As a user of uBlock Origin, I do have the ability to add custom filters to block DOM elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Matthew Griffith, &#34;Why Elm&#34;</title>
      <link>/blog/book-notes-matthew-griffith-why-elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book-notes-matthew-griffith-why-elm/</guid>
      <description>Elm incorporates some of the advances from the last 40 years of programming design without learning academic jargon Many pain points of frontend development don&amp;rsquo;t exist in Elm - nulls, undefined is not a function - and runtime exceptions are extremely rare Static typing, compile time checks, friendly error messages, type signature inference Some experience Elm programmers will start a program by sketching out the type signatures first to get a high-level view of what the various APIs will be, organization will look like and create a specification for the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Rsync to efficiently backup (mirror) hard drives</title>
      <link>/blog/using-rsync-to-efficiently-backup-mirror-hard-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-rsync-to-efficiently-backup-mirror-hard-drives/</guid>
      <description>The concepts discussed here are not Raspberry Pi specific and can easily be adapted for other uses.  Background I have a Raspberry Pi setup with an external hard drive that is accessible over Samba. It&amp;rsquo;s be quite reliable so far, but I wanted to backup the data to another external drive hooked up to the same Raspberry Pi.
I found a simple solution to this problem using Rsync and Systemd timers (as opposed to installing Cron and learning Cron, but if you wish, you can substitute Systemd with Cron).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to access the McMaster CAS virtual machines on Linux host</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-access-the-mcmaster-cas-virtual-machines-on-linux-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-access-the-mcmaster-cas-virtual-machines-on-linux-host/</guid>
      <description>There is a web client available, but still requires a connect to the VPN. See CAS wiki[ref 1] for more information.  Using openconnect Install openconenct
openconnect sslvpn.mcmaster.ca (try with sudo if it fails)
If nothing failed, you should be connected
Tested on Xubuntu and Debian (x86_64).
Download the VPN client for linux, *.tar.gz from https://www.mcmaster.ca/uts/network/vpn/
Download the VMWare Horizon client, *bundle from https://www.vmware.com/go/viewclients
cd to the location of both downloads</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Knights Who say... Ni</title>
      <link>/blog/the-knights-who-say...-ni/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-knights-who-say...-ni/</guid>
      <description> We are no longer the knights who say Ni! We are now the knights who say ekki-ekki-ekki-pitang-zoom-boing! Monty Python
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>