<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on francium</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on francium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting TLS certificates for internal HTTPs websites</title><link>/blog/2023-07-31-internal-website-https-certs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023-07-31-internal-website-https-certs/</guid><description>A short guide on acquiring Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt TLS certificates for internal websites using the DNS challenge.</description></item><item><title>Rendering React components to a HTML string in Deno</title><link>/blog/2022-09-18-deno-react-rendertostring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022-09-18-deno-react-rendertostring/</guid><description>This is a minimal example of using React in Deno and rendering a React component into a HTML string.</description></item><item><title>Exception debugging or: How to abuse JavaScript exception and debug tests</title><link>/blog/2022-06-23-exception-debugging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022-06-23-exception-debugging/</guid><description>Exceptional abuse of exceptions</description></item><item><title>The limits of TypeScript's Template Literal types</title><link>/blog/2021-12-16-the-limits-of-typescripts-template-literal-types/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-12-16-the-limits-of-typescripts-template-literal-types/</guid><description>How far can you push TypeScript&amp;rsquo;s Template Literal types?</description></item><item><title>Mostly useful or: How I learned to stop typing and write a few Bash aliases</title><link>/blog/2021-11-19-bash-aliases/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-11-19-bash-aliases/</guid><description>A very short list of a few interesting Bash aliases. Featuring: quitting vim, theming apps, and fun pipes</description></item><item><title>Making delegation easier in JavaScript (TypeScript)</title><link>/blog/2020-08-22-making-delegation-easier-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-08-22-making-delegation-easier-in-javascript/</guid><description>Using metaprogramming to enable easier method delegation</description></item><item><title>React Hooks: A very brief intro</title><link>/blog/2020-08-07-react-hooks-brief-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-08-07-react-hooks-brief-intro/</guid><description>React Hooks API appears to be a immediate-mode layer on top of the traditional retained-mode style React system.
Internally, the library knows which component is currently being rendered and since a hook can only be called from a React component function or another hook, React is able to keep track of function calls to the hook APIs to &amp;lsquo;magically&amp;rsquo; manage state without being explicit about function calls across multiple render cycles.</description></item><item><title>Trigger bash commands in a Docker container from host</title><link>/blog/2020-04-18-trigger-command-in-docker-container/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 15:38:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-18-trigger-command-in-docker-container/</guid><description>Here is an easy way to trigger a command inside a docker container. One use case of this is to trigger a compiler, which is running inside a container, to recompile sources.
Make sure inotify-tools is installed on the container, apt install inotify-tools (Debian/Ubuntu), pacman -S inotify-tools (Arch). It&amp;rsquo;s also assumed some directory is mounted on the container which the host can write to and container can read.
The trick here is a .</description></item><item><title>An Implementation of Parallel Shearshort in C using PThreads</title><link>/blog/implementation-of-parallel-shearort-in-c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/implementation-of-parallel-shearort-in-c/</guid><description>This will be a look at a parallel implementation of Shearsort using POSIX Threads (PThreads) in the C programming language.
This is not meant to be an efficient or optimal implementation, nor should it be considered production ready code. This is purely an educational exercise. I&amp;rsquo;m also not a seasoned C/C++ developer, so expect some errors or downright stupidity here and there. If you have any suggestions for improvements feel free to create an issue on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>GNOME Mutli-Monitor Workspace Fix (Gnome 3.30)</title><link>/blog/gnome-mutli-monitor-workspace-fix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 20:18:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/gnome-mutli-monitor-workspace-fix/</guid><description>workspaces_only_on_primary setting is suppose to make workspaces work correctly [1] in a multi-monitor setup.
There are older articles on the internet about enabling this option, but they won&amp;rsquo;t work with newer versions of GNOME. Prior to 3.30, I was using a very similar command which was described by Greg Cordts in his post on the subject.
After upgrading to GNOME 3.30, this way of enabling the option stopped working. After reporting this to the GNOME team as a bug, two individuals provided some very useful information,</description></item><item><title>Hide YouTube's "Recommended For You" suggestions</title><link>/blog/hide-youtube-recommended-videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 19:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/hide-youtube-recommended-videos/</guid><description>One thing I find quite annoying with YouTube is &amp;ldquo;Recommended For You&amp;rdquo; spam in the related videos section. I do not sign into YouTube and use Firefox Containers so most &amp;ldquo;Recommended For You&amp;rdquo; videos are irrelevant, distracting, and seem suspiciously like they&amp;rsquo;ve been paid for (I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is true).
As a user of uBlock Origin, I do have the ability to add custom filters to block DOM elements.</description></item><item><title>Using Rsync to efficiently backup (mirror) hard drives</title><link>/blog/using-rsync-to-backup-mirror-drives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-rsync-to-backup-mirror-drives/</guid><description>The concepts discussed here are not Raspberry Pi specific and can easily be adapted for other uses. Background I have a Raspberry Pi setup with an external hard drive that is accessible over Samba. It&amp;rsquo;s be quite reliable so far, but I wanted to backup the data to another external drive hooked up to the same Raspberry Pi.
I found a simple solution to this problem using Rsync and Systemd timers (as opposed to installing Cron and learning Cron, but if you wish, you can substitute Systemd with Cron).</description></item></channel></rss>